Logan Natysin

Summary

Software Engineer with 4 years of experience in designing, creating, testing and implementing various software applications. Skilled at working with Python, Java, C, and SQL. Uses these skill to contribute in a collaborative team environment, while contributing to an organization's success in delivering top quality solutions to clients by creating the best user experience.

Education

Virginia Polytechnic Institute & State University

Dec. 2024

B.S. Computer Science - Dean's List (x6)

GPA: 3.60/4.0

Skills

Languages: Python, Java, C, SQL

Tools: MYSQL, Flask, Jupyter Notebooks, Git/GitHub, Docker, Unix Shell, VS Code, Eclipse, PyCharm, Overleaf, MATLAB, Microsoft Office Software

Experience

Noblis - Reston, VA | Autonomous Systems Intern

Jun. 2024 - Aug. 2024

- Developed and modified a distributed asynchronous network application for autonomous vehicles.
- Engineered a trust-based task assignment system, improving task completion efficiency.
- Created a robust system for task assignment based on trust and vehicle availability.
- Enhanced system robustness and efficiency by enabling operation with or without communication.
- Simulated real-world communication between autonomous vehicles using Docker.
- Implemented a unique identity service for autonomous vehicles using SSH keys for secure communication.
- Tools/Skills Used: Python, SQL, Docker, Git/GitHub, TCP networking, Multi-Threading, Robot Operating Systems.

Stonewall Golf Club - Gainesville, VA | Starter/Cart Attendant

Jun. 2021 - May 2024

- Enhanced customer service capabilities by engaging with over 100 customers daily, leading to a increase in customer satisfaction scores.
- · Managed time and resolved issues to ensure efficient golfer movement, enhancing customer experience.

Kappa Delta Rho | Pontifex and Service Chairman

Feb. 2023 - Dec. 2024

- Founding member of Gamma Beta chapter at Virginia Tech.
- Led brotherhood conduct and conflict resolution as Pontifex.
- Organized and planned all community service opportunities as Service Chairman, tracking project completion hours for members.

Projects

Project Discovery Portal for CS4264 | Python, Flask, SQL, MYSQL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git/GitHub, VS Code

Dec. 2024

- Designed and created a web application for project management in the CS4264 capstone class.
- Simplified project assignment for professors by creating a user-friendly interface.
- · Led backend development, designing the database with SQL, APIs with Flask, and backend code with Python.
- Implemented user authentication and role-based access control to ensure secure project management.
- Integrated real-time notifications and updates to keep users informed about project status.
- Conducted user testing and gathered feedback to improve the application's usability and functionality.

YourCloset | Python, SQL, MYSQL, tkinter, Git/GitHub, VS Code

Oct. 2024

- Engineered and launched YourCloset, a social media application based around a users closet.
- Developed frontend GUI with Python and connected backend to a MySQL database.
- Enabled users to manage their closet items and interact socially within the application.
- Implemented features for users to add, manage, view, delete, and update items in their closet.
- Developed a social aspect allowing users to view and interact with each other's closets.
- Ensured data security and privacy by implementing secure authentication and authorization mechanisms.

$\textbf{Personal Web Server} \mid \textit{C, HTTP, TCP, Git, Unix Shell, VS Code}$

Nov. 2023

- Developed a personal web server using HTTP and TCP protocols.
- · Implemented multithreading for multiple clients, user authentication, and video streaming.
- Optimized server performance to handle high traffic and ensure low latency.
- Integrated logging and monitoring tools to track server performance and troubleshoot issues.
- Deployed a Svelte app on the server to demonstrate its capabilities.